Finishing Treatment
Once your course of radiation
treatment is done,
you will be provided with instructions
and next steps.
If your overall oncology plan
is to continue with systemic treatment,
you will meet with your medical oncologist
to discuss next steps.
From a radiation point of view,
your follow up care will be
with the same radiation oncologist
who planned your radiation.
The timeline
depends on your specific treatment,
but generally patients see their radiation
oncologist in a return visit
2 to 3 months after treatment,
with the option to return earlier
or contact the office at any time
if there are pressing concerns.
Your doctor may order labs
or imaging to monitor
the effects of treatment.
Typically, imaging you had prior to radiation will be repeated.
Other possible follow up strategies include:
ctDNA Testing & a symptom survey.
ctDNA testing is blood work that looks specifically for DNA
from your tumor that could be detected in your blood,
called circulating tumor DNA or ctDNA. Your doctor will talk to you more about this.
As mentioned previously,
any side effects of radiation that you
experienced during the course of treatment
should begin to subside after finishing
with gradual improvement over time.
If you continue to note symptoms,
please let your doctor know as
there are medications are other therapies
that can help manage them.